[Music]
[Música]
consider that you consider that television was much
considera que consideras que era mucho
better in the time of
mejor la televisión de la época de
Martian Chronicles and all that, not
crónicas marcianas y demás no
with a program like the ones they do now,
con un programa de los que hacen ahora
come on, it doesn't make sense because it
vamos no tiene sentido porque es que no
has nothing to do with the program.
tiene nada que ver desde el programa
Well, everything to the content, everything
Bueno pues todo al contenido todo no
has nothing to do with
tiene nada que
Verónica Marcela fundamentally
Verónica Marcela fundamentalmente
and what there is now is a
y esto que hay ahora pues es una
carnage, that
carnicería nada más
's all the difference. How do you start your
son la diferencia Cómo comienzas tú tu
journey in
andadura en
television, the first thing is Chronicles, no, no, the first thing,
la tele lo primero es crónicas no no lo
the first program that I think of
primero el primer programa que pienso yo
is Tombola Tombola.
es Tómbola Tómbola
Yes, but let's go to a program, I go to Tombola
Sí pero vamos un programa voy a Tómbola
because I had already sold the photos of
porque ya había vendido las fotos de
Mar Flores' interview, they paid me an
interview de mar flores me pagaron una
impressive amount of money, I didn't know that
millonada impresionante yo no sabía que
television paid that much
la televisión pagaba tanto
and from there I went to Chronicle. Yes, they are in
y de ahí fui a Crónica Sí están en
Chronicles, they take ten minutes to show
crónicas a los diez minutos tardan
that it was an interview because
que fue una entrevista porque se sabía
the audience ratings were known, it was historic, do you
las audiencias fue una cosa histórica te
remember?
acuerdas
Well, 40%,
Pues el 40%
but come on,
pero vamos luego
many times in fact, I have the
muchas veces De hecho tengo el récord
European audience record. I have a 92%
europeo de audiencia Yo tengo un 92% de
audience, 92% has been reached
audiencia un 92% se ha llegado
on a salsa program. Rosa, I don't know what her
en un programa de salsa Rosa no sé cómo
name was.  telecinco salsa Rosa It was
se llamaba de telecinco salsa Rosa Era
one of a certain Santi I don't remember
uno de un tal Santi que no me acuerdo
the name or surname of the
cómo se llamaba el apellidos
director's husband
el marido de la directora
And what the program was about that night,
Y de qué trataba esa noche del programa
well I don't remember I think it was the
pues no me acuerdo Yo creo que fue el
day he said he was leaving chronicles or
día que decía abandonar crónicas o a los
two days later, well that week
dos días bueno esa semana
and the photo is that of Mar Flores, that
y la foto es esa de mar flores eso
was a tremendous scandal, that's good to
fueron un escándalo tremendo eso bueno
put it into context because there are
para ponerle un contexto porque hay
people who are watching us from all over,
gente que nos está viendo de todos lados
Mar Flores was a very famous model in
mar flores era una modelo muy famosa de
fact I think your brother represented her,
hecho yo creo que tu hermano la
yes no I mean like, and she was like
sí no O sea en plan y y ella estaba como
involved with Alessandro Lequio And
enrollada con Alessandro lequio Y
then they themselves took some
entonces ellos mismos hicieron unas
photos in bed, no, no, it's not like that No,
fotos en la cama no no es así No ella
she, officially,
ella oficialmente
that she would later marry a friend of hers,
que luego se casaría con una amiga suya
de Flores, no, but he was the president of
de flores no pero él era el presidente
Madrid's businessmen
madrileña de empresarios
and he will be a man who had an
y él será un hombre que tenía una
importance, let's
importancia
say,
digamos
socially, not within what was Spanish life
social no dentro de lo que era la vida
and suddenly some photos come out of
y de repente pues salen algunas fotos de
Mar Flores laughing at Fernández Tapia
mar flores riéndose de Fernández Tapia
with Alejandro in a bed in a hotel in
con alexandro en una cama en un hotel en
Rome, opening the interview that
Roma abriendo la entrevista que había
she had given when thanking, I think I remember that it
dado ella al agradecer creo recordar que
was the one in which she said that she loved
era en el que decía que quería mucho
Fernando Tapias very much, the intention  with which
Fernando Tapias la intención con la que
those photos were taken Well I don't know which ones
se hicieron esas fotos Pues no sé cuáles
they are no Because I would have to ask
son no Porque habría que preguntárselo a
her but what is true is that one day
ella pero lo que sí es cierto que un día
my brother took me and told me if I
me llevó mi hermano y me dijo que si
wanted to negotiate those interior photos
quería negociar esas fotos en interior
that they had given them early
que se las habían temprano
Miguel had already given them early I know
ya les había regalado Miguel temprano sé
that he had been a partner of Alessandro
que había sido socio de Alessandro
In short I went to negotiate those photos they
Total que yo fui a negociar las fotos
gave me a lot of millions and
esas me dieron un montón de millones y
from there I received nothing more than a million
de ahí no recibí nada más que un millón
and how much was there in total do you remember I think it
y cuántos eran en total te acuerdas creo
was 60
que eran 60
the truth is I don't remember well but they
la verdad no me acuerdo bien pero se
eat them there
comen los
were 30 3:30
fueron 30 las 3:30
and I arrived at the office which was 200
y llegué al despacho que tenía 200
meters
metros
like a trigger
como como un gatillo
full of bills because that was in
lleno de billetes porque eso que era en
black in part or how
negro en parte o cómo
if they are achieved in black what happens half what
si se logran negro lo que pasa la mitad
happens is that then I washed it
lo que pasa es que luego lo lavé
Yes but let's go I didn't wash it my
Sí pero vamos no lo lavé yo lo lavó mi
brother washed it
hermano
Yes what did he give me I didn't ask for
Sí qué es lo que me dio yo no le pedí
anything or anything it seemed very little to me because it
nada ni nada me pareció bien poco porque
seems to me that he wanted what he told me 25 to
él me parece que quería que me dijo 25 a
but that is a tradition of your brother
pero eso es una tradición de tu hermano
it is revenge to love flowers because Marc
es una venganza amar flores porque Marc
flowers was going to  fire because he had
flores lo iba a despedir porque él había
separated from Mar Flores's sister and
separado de la hermana de mar flores y
was involved with
estaba enrollado con
Clearly
claro
so that people know the good the
para que la gente lo sepa la bueno la
mother of the children of most of the
madre de los hijos de la mayoría de los
children except one of Kiko Matamoros is the
hijos menos una de Kiko Matamoros es
sister of the person he removed
hermana de la persona a la que quitó
represented Mar Flores's sister who
representaba hermana de mar flores que
was also my girlfriend before being
además fue el novia mía antes de ser
my brother's girlfriend the mother of
novia de mi hermano la madre de los
your brother's children was your girlfriend yes and
hijos de tu hermano fue novia tuya sí y
that you also had something no
con que también tuviste algo no
also No because he goes around collecting what
también No porque él va recogiendo lo
I
que yo
didn't share
no compartimos
[Music]
[Música]
the only time the last time you
la única vez que la última vez que
were still light this that was
fuiste aún de luz esto que fue hace ya
more years ago than the most that also he got
más años que la más que además él se
very angry No because as it came out it came out
cabreó mucho No porque como salió salió
yesterday
ayer
mother of God Hey but that photo of Mar
madre de Dios Oye pero esa foto de mar
Flores was
flores eran
intimate there were legal consequences with
íntimas hubo consecuencias legales con
that they
eso
voluntarily take
se hacen voluntariamente
some photos and also Leo first tries to
unas fotos y además Leo primero intenta
sell them to interview what happens is that he
venderlas a interview lo que pasa es que
asked for 100 million
les pidió 100 millones
intervened drink and well once
intervino trago y bueno una vez que
someone has wanted to sell their privacy they
alguien ha querido vender su intimidad
no longer have privacy of course no That is very
ya no tiene intimidad claro no Eso está
clear the law
clarísimo la ley
And from there your journey begins no I
Y a partir de ahí empieza tu andadura no
mean first you do an interview  in
O sea primero haces una entrevista en
Tombola which would be the host they didn't
Tómbola que sería la [__] no
dedicate a bunch of columns in the
dedicaron un montón de columnas en el
opinion article that had nothing
artículo de opinión que no tenía nada
to do with television
que ver con la televisión
[Music]
[Música]
And well then there to chronicles and well And
Y bueno pues ahí a crónicas y bueno Y
also I covered a world that I didn't
además ya cubrí un mundo que que no
know I mean for me television
conocía Es decir para mí la televisión
I had never seen chronicles in my life
yo no había visto crónicas en mi vida
but you liked that world you were interested in
pero te gustaba ese mundo te interesaba
something well
algo bueno
I went to Crónica if I didn't really
yo iba en Crónica si no sabía realmente
even know who we were talking about
ni de quién estábamos hablando
but come on and if a Cuban came on who
pero vamos y si salía un cubano que se
had hooked up with Marujita Díaz who
había enrollado con marujita Díaz que
was 70 years old well it was easy to analyze the
tenía 70 años pues era fácil analizar la
situation it
situación no
's not an easy topic to digest to see
es un tema facilito de digerir a ver
gossip and the heart what you have that
salseo y el corazón lo que tienes eso no
sometimes not more entertaining more
algunas veces más entretenido más
fun but what you have which is
divertido pero lo que tienes que es
simple is not for very very
sencillito no es para mente muy muy
privileged and very complicated minds and And how did they
privilegiadas y muy complicadas y Y cómo
notice you and Javier
fue que se fijaron en ti y Javier
saldate uses a proposal
saldate usa una propuesta
on the table and we went to a
en la mesa y fuimos a un corte de
commercial break and Javier came out running and
publicidad y salió corriendo Javier y me
said to me Hey you have to work with me
dijo Oye que tienes que trabajar conmigo
and when he told me I'll see a figure
y a mí cuando me dijo me veo una cifra
because I asked him and I said but
porque yo le pregunté y dije pero por
how much this is not  turn off
Cuánto esto no se apaga
how wonderful do you remember the figure Yes
qué maravilla te acuerdas de la cifra Sí
in principle It was
en principio Fueron
200,000 per program what happens is that
200.000 por programa lo que pasa es que
charging 18,000 euros per program
cobrando 18.000 euros por programa
and books per program at the time
y libros por programa en la época
my goodness thanks a month almost a
madre mía gracias al mes casi
lot of money Because also once more or
mucho dinero Porque además una vez más o
less well I did a weekend program
menos pues me hacía un programa de fin
that could rarely go below
de semana que raramente podía bajar de
70-80,000 my goodness What happens What happened
70-80.000 madre mía Qué pasa Qué pasó no
is not like that That was the golden age of
es así Esa fue la época dorada en la
television where you earned a lot of
televisión donde se ganaba muchísimo
money and it doesn't mean that I earned it from
dinero y no quiere decir que lo ganara a
everyone or anything but yes for
todo el mundo ni mucho menos pero sí por
example
ejemplo
maybe I earned a thousand euros no that now
a lo mejor ganaba mil euros no que ahora
imagine they would clap with their ears
imagínate darían Palmas con las orejas
Of course
Claro
at that time these people from
en aquella época esta gente de los
Big Brother if I'm not mistaken
grandes hermanos si no me equivoco
had like a contract since they entered I do
tenían como un contrato ya que entraban
n't know if it was an urban legend or it was
en no sé si era una leyenda urbana o era
a contract wanted from Big Brother they
un contrato quería de gran hermano
had the right to be interviewed in
tenían derecho para ser entrevistado en
chronicles everything was already at the same price
crónicas ya iba todo en el mismo precio
They had their rights they charged
Ellos tenían sus derechos ellos cobraban
very little for a program Maybe they
muy poco por un programa A lo mejor
charged 200 or 300 euros
cobraban 200 o 300 euros
And you with
Y tú con
these people with the collaborators because
esta gente con los colaboradores porque
you within Martian Chronicles you
tú dentro de crónicas marcianas tú
were in the press part Rosa no I
estabas en la parte de la prensa Rosa no
mean you the political part
O sea tú la parte política
with the rest of the collaborators how about
con el resto de colaboradores qué tal
because from there it came out I
porque de ahí ha salido
had nothing to do with them nor was I
no tenía nada que ver con ellos ni me
interested in the subject that was discussed and nothing to
interesaba el tema que trataba y nada
do In fact I didn't go to the meeting
que ver Es más yo no iba a la reunión
and I would leave five minutes later I didn't
y me iba cinco minutos después ni
even put on makeup imagine
siquiera me maquillaba imagínate
you for example with Mila Ximénez I don't know if you
tú por ejemplo con Mila ximénez No sé si
saw that Well I
viste que Bueno antes
met her long before in the year 90 we
la conocí mucho antes en el año 90
wanted a restaurant in Seville
queríamos que un restaurante en Sevilla
I met her So you've been around
la conocí a ella Entonces has estado por
here in Seville I
aquí por Sevilla
had a restaurant on Betis street
tuve un restaurante en la calle betis
called Carmen which is where
que se llamaba Carmen que es donde está
the bullfighting is now
ahora el rejoneo
and another place Because they are two places
y otro local Porque son dos locales
in fact Jesús Quintero
de hecho Jesús Quintero
my best friend has had a
mi mejor amigo
relationship the last few years Of
tiene tenía relación los últimos años
course yes he has continued maintaining I mean
Claro sí ha seguido manteniendo la O sea
practically until the last few days not
prácticamente hasta los últimos días no
at the end
al final
and with saddada no no well I don't
y con saddada no no bueno no
have friendship but but I don't have the
tenga amistad pero pero no tengo la
relationship that I had with Jesús with
relación que tenía con Jesús yo con
Jesús
Jesús
the only gift or the only good thing that I
el único regalo o el único bueno que
keep from television and that
guardo de la televisión y ese
knowledge
conocimiento
There were many many comments out there that
Hubo mucho muchos comentarios por ahí
said that it was because you made him
que decían que era porque tú le hiciste
like an I don't know if it will be a  hoax like
como una no sé si será un bulo como que
you gave him a bad answer in the middle of a program
tú le hiciste en medio de un programa
or something like that and he got
una mala contestación o algo así y se
offended like suck my dick or something like that they
ofendió como Chúpame la [__] o algo así
said
decían
[Music]
[Música]
madness no
la locura no
no what I called him some [ __ ] or
no lo que lo llamé a unos [__] o
one I don't remember
una no me acuerdo
the usual way of changing but
lo habitual la manera de cambio pero
let's no problem on the
vamos a ningún problema todo lo
contrary
contrario
if he didn't want to work then he should let
si no quería trabajar pues que dejara
the season pass he would pay me
pasar la temporada que me pagaría a mí
whatever he was earning and that
lo que fuera lo que estaba ganando y que
the seasons
las temporadas
because there came a time when I was bored of
porque llegó un momento que me aburría
doing it
hacerlo
But he behaved well with people not
Pero él se portaba bien con la gente no
with me there
conmigo
was a controversy last year because
hubo una polémica el año pasado porque
there were people who had come out of chronicles
había gente que había salido de crónicas
who said one thing and other people who
que decía una cosa y otra gente que
said the opposite Do
decía lo contrario
you remember that Martian Chronicles whether it
Tú recuerdas que crónicas marcianas
was natural or scripted was
fuera natural o era guionizado estaba
ionized in part
ionizado en parte
because they brought it together no and then
porque ellos lo reunían no y entonces
well you have to defend this or
pues tú tienes que defender a esto o
who wants to defend themselves
quién quiere defenderse
So they more or less distributed the game
Entonces repartían más o menos el juego
because lynching on television
porque el linchamiento en la televisión
is very ugly it is the effect that arises
es muy feo es el efecto que que surgen
in the viewer of seeing that all the
en el espectador de ver que todas las
people are attacking someone who perhaps
personas están atacando a uno que a lo
is not present or has the right
mejor no está presente ni tiene derecho
to defend themselves Well that's it So
a defenderse Pues eso
these are infected
Entonces estos son contagiados
The problem is that those who were in
El problema es que los que les
charge of defending ended up
encargaban que que defendieran acababan
attacking they were in
atacando
charge of attacking they ended up
se encargaban que atacaran acababan
defending because their phones didn't have
defendiendo porque sus teléfonos no
much capacity
daban para mucho
and this was enough to carry a script
y esto era suficiente llevar un guión
on a topic that is about opinion and debate
en un tema que es de opinión y de debate
or rather good
o sea bueno
debate they don't know how to do anything I
debatir ni saben hacer nada
was having dinner with Javier and I asked him
Estaba cenando con Javier y le pregunté
uncle why do you have so many idiots here
tío tú por qué tienes tantos tontos aquí
on the program he didn't tell me the idiot is
en el programa no me dijo el tonto eres
you he says because television has to
tú dice porque la televisión tiene que
be made up of idiots and crazy people
estar compuesta de tontos y de locos
So choose and I say Well then I
Así que elige y digo Bueno pues yo
prefer to be crazy
prefiero ser loco
but soon it will be But come on I had no
pero pronto será Pero vamos no tenía ni
way of understanding them and in fact they are
por dónde cogerlos y de hecho
called seriously well that's the color of
se llaman en serio pues eso el color de
the Barajas of a folkloric or the
las Barajas de una folclórica o los
romances of Isabel's daughter I know
romances de la hija de Isabel yo que sé
anything you
cualquier cosa
saw there
viste
was a click that is because of
hubo un click que es de los porque de
Crónica marciana there is one thing that makes me
Crónica marciana hay una cosa que me da
very sad and that is that it is very complicated to
mucha pena y es que es muy complicado
rescue the programs they do not have them
rescatar a los programas no los tienen
uploaded anywhere or anything unless it
subidos en ninguna parte ni nada como no
is people who have some clicks uploaded it on the
sea gente que tiene algún clic subió en
internet and little else there is one that circulates
internet y poco más hay uno que que rula
a lot  over the internet what is your discussion
mucho por internet que es tu discusión
with Carlos yoya remember
con Carlos yoya recuerda
well
bueno
as someone very aggressive
como alguien muy agresivo
in fact Well until the
de hecho Bueno hasta la conferencia
episcopal conference we have forgotten
episcoparan nos hemos olvidado
And well the character was
Y bueno pues el personaje era
fundamentally basic he was very primary he did
fundamentalmente básico era muy primario
not have a sense of honor and all that that
no tenía un sentido del honor y todo eso
the poor have because the poor
que tienen los pobres porque los pobres
because the sense of honor is free it is
porque el sentido del honor es gratis es
the only thing they can have so well
lo único que pueden tener entonces pues
for everything he was offended he was not a very very
bueno por todo se ofendía no era un tipo
cool guy But then you know him well he was
chulo Pero luego se le conoces pues era
a guy who had certain
un tipo que tenía ciertas cierta
humanity Although now apparently well
humanidad Aunque ahora por lo visto
well he is involved in a very
bueno pues se anda metido en un lío muy
big mess and he has not shown to have that
gordo y no ha demostrado tener esa
humanity no but come on I am not the
humanidad no pero vamos yo tampoco soy
one to judge him because of
quien para juzgarle porque
those circumstances really what has
esas circunstancias realmente lo que ha
happened
pasado
But it is true that when he for example
Pero es verdad que él cuando por ejemplo
told you in the on the plate he threw
te decía en el en el plato te echaba
balls at you no Hey I'll put it in you I'll put it in that is
huevos no Oye te meto te meto eso es
true
verdad
to you your brother had to throw
a ti a tu hermano había que echar los
balls eh
huevos eh
but there would be a lot of
pero mucho
television more well
de televisión faltaría más bueno
listen to me there were some that Well in
escúchame había algunos que Bueno de
fact recently Kiko Hernández said I do
hecho hace poco el Kiko Hernández dijo
n't know if you would be that the jewels hit
No sé si tú estaría que el joyas le pegó
Antonio there was a hit
Antonio había una [__]
Monroe
la Monroe
hit Enrique del pozo that
pegarle a Enrique del pozo eso
hit him with a cucumber in  the face because
le pegó con un pepino en la cara porque
a Catalan who was Rayo's girlfriend I
una catalana que la que fue novia de
don't fall now for sure the people in the
no caigo ahora seguro que la gente de la
audience and that hit him with a cucumber
audiencia y que le pegó con un pepino
well and Antonio David grabbed the
bueno y Antonio David le cogió del
coconut baby by the neck too I do
pescuezo al coco guagua también
n't know if it was a show or if it was serious
no sé si sería show o sería en serio
but the image
pero la imagen
[Music]
[Música]
effectively they did
efectivamente
n't throw and effectively
no echaron y efectivamente
Well but he can resurrect at
Bueno pero él puede resucitar en
any moment like Albano's daughter
cualquier momento como la hija de albano
they can resurrect her at any moment
la pueden resucitar en cualquier momento
you really like black humor I don't
te gusta mucho el humor negro no
like humor I think you have to
me gusta el humor creo que hay que
laugh constantly no and more with these
reírse constantemente no y más con estos
topics Well you have to laugh no because if
temas Pues tienes que reir no porque si
you take this Seriously you have to go to the
te tomas esto En serio te tienes que ir
psychiatrist better than cry
al psiquiatra mejor que llorar
If today they offered you something
Si a día de hoy te ofrecieran alguna
little of this
cosita de esta de
reality
realtitis
television interviews like with
entrevistas en televisión en plan con
a lot of money not crazy no they won't continue
mucha pasta ni loco no no lo siguen
maintaining it because I think that since
manteniendo porque eso creo que desde el
2013 which was the last time you stepped on
2013 que fue la última vez que pisaste
a set you have fulfilled it and crazy There is
un plató lo has cumplido y loco Es que
no price I mean compensation
no hay precio Es decir compensación por
anywhere
ningún sitio
[Music]
[Música]